<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-13T22:59:18+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Q-ACS</title><subtitle>Queen’s University International Student Chapter of the American Chemical Society (Q-ACS).</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Empowering Future Leaders - Professional Development Initiatives by Q-ACS</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/06/08/pro-dev.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Empowering Future Leaders - Professional Development Initiatives by Q-ACS" /><published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-13T22:56:24+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2023/06/08/pro-dev</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/06/08/pro-dev.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>Q-ACS is dedicated to nurturing the academic and professional growth of the department. This year, the chapter launched a series of three enriching workshops, along with the introduction of a Professional Development Travel Award, aimed at providing the students and postdocs with essential skills and opportunities.</p>

<p>1. Data Analysis Overview by Dr. Randy Ellis</p>

<p>Kicking off its professional development series, Q-ACS welcomed Dr. Randy Ellis from Queen’s University’s School of Computing and Department of Surgery to lead an enriching “Data Analysis Overview” workshop. This session was tailored to the unique needs of chemistry students and professionals, focusing on data analysis techniques directly applicable to their field.</p>

<p>2. Presentation Skills by ACS Fellow Dr. Mark Jones</p>

<p>Communication is paramount in any profession. Dr. Mark Jones, an ACS Fellow and renowned expert, conducted the “Presentation Skills” workshop, teaching the art of delivering compelling presentations and captivating audiences. These skills not only enhance professional growth but also enable members to effectively share their research.</p>

<p>3. Career Kick-Starter: Preparing for a Successful Career by ACS Fellow Dr. Ajay Mallia</p>

<p>The “Career Kick-Starter” workshop, led by ACS Fellow, Dr. Ajay Mallia, addressed the challenges of transitioning from graduate school to a successful career. Attendees gained insights into resume building, job searching strategies, and interview preparation, boosting their confidence to navigate the professional world.</p>

<p>In addition to these workshops, Q-ACS introduced its inaugural Professional Development Travel Award. This initiative reflects the chapter’s commitment to supporting members’ growth and career aspirations. Three chemistry students were granted the opportunity to attend the “Women Creating a More Sustainable World Conference.” This experience not only exposed them to cutting-edge research and networking but also aligned with the chapter’s values of sustainability and inclusivity.</p>

<p>In conclusion, Q-ACS is at the forefront of cultivating the next generation of chemistry leaders. Through these workshops and the Professional Development Travel Award, the chapter empowers its members with essential skills, knowledge, and valuable opportunities. As Q-ACS continues to invest in its members’ growth, it sets a shining example for the future of chemistry and beyond.</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Data Analysis Overview workshop by Dr. Randy Ellis">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/randy_ellis_workshop.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Data Analysis Overview workshop by Dr. Randy Ellis" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Data Analysis Overview workshop by Dr. Randy Ellis

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Career Kick-Starter workshop by ACS Fellow Dr. Ajay Mallia">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/pro-dev.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Career Kick-Starter workshop by ACS Fellow Dr. Ajay Mallia" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Career Kick-Starter workshop by ACS Fellow Dr. Ajay Mallia

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Malek Hassan</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recognizing Our Community Leaders in Chemical Sciences</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/04/03/EDII-awards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recognizing Our Community Leaders in Chemical Sciences" /><published>2023-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-13T22:56:24+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2023/04/03/EDII-awards</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/04/03/EDII-awards.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>Q-ACS held two recognition programs to honor Queen’s community leaders in the chemical sciences and recognized the awardees with commemorating plaques during the Chapter’s spring reception.</p>

<p>In August 2022, the “Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program” was established to promote talented graduate students and postdocs demonstrating leadership in mentoring, promotion of DEIR, and promotion of research safety. The Q-ACS capitalized on the department’s nominations and, as a result, ACS recognized six Queen’s members (one graduate student and one postdoctoral scholar in each category).</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="The 2022 Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program Award Recipients. Pictured left-to-right: Dr. Lishen Zang (Mentorship), Dr. Roberto Nolla-Saltiel (Research Safety), Andre Castillo (Mentorship), Malek Hassan (Research Safety), Dr. Shideh Ahmadi (DEIR), and Jennifer McLeod (DEIR)">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/GSPSRP_2022.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="The 2022 Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program Award Recipients. Pictured left-to-right: Dr. Lishen Zang (Mentorship), Dr. Roberto Nolla-Saltiel (Research Safety), Andre Castillo (Mentorship), Malek Hassan (Research Safety), Dr. Shideh Ahmadi (DEIR), and Jennifer McLeod (DEIR)" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      The 2022 Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program Award Recipients. Pictured left-to-right: Dr. Lishen Zang (Mentorship), Dr. Roberto Nolla-Saltiel (Research Safety), Andre Castillo (Mentorship), Malek Hassan (Research Safety), Dr. Shideh Ahmadi (DEIR), and Jennifer McLeod (DEIR)

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>

<p>In addition, Q-ACS instituted “Excellence Awards Program”, modelled based on the ACS Salutes to Excellence program, to underscore outstanding accomplishments or achievements of service by external partners who have made a positive impact on everyday life or who have helped contribute to greater public awareness of chemistry. Q-ACS awarded:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Excellence in EDII to QC-IDEAS (received by Ayden Harrison)</li>
  <li>Initiatives Excellence to Department of Chemistry’s “Hand Sanitizer Project” during the COVID-19 pandemic (received by Dr. Richard Oleschuk)</li>
  <li>Alumni Excellence to Dr. Alex Veinot.</li>
</ol>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Ayden Harrison (left) receiving the Q-ACS Excellence Award on behalf of QC-IDEAS, Dr. Richard Oleschuk (right) receiving the Q-ACS Excellence Awards on behalf of the Queen’s Chemistry, and Alex Veinot (not pictured) received the Q-ACS alumni excellence award.">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/excellence_awards_2022.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Ayden Harrison (left) receiving the Q-ACS Excellence Award on behalf of QC-IDEAS, Dr. Richard Oleschuk (right) receiving the Q-ACS Excellence Awards on behalf of the Queen’s Chemistry, and Alex Veinot (not pictured) received the Q-ACS alumni excellence award." loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Ayden Harrison (left) receiving the Q-ACS Excellence Award on behalf of QC-IDEAS, Dr. Richard Oleschuk (right) receiving the Q-ACS Excellence Awards on behalf of the Queen’s Chemistry, and Alex Veinot (not pictured) received the Q-ACS alumni excellence award.

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Mark McKeown</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating EDII in the Chemical Sciences</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating EDII in the Chemical Sciences" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-13T22:56:24+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>On March 30, 2023, Q-ACS hosted its largest event of 2022-2023: the chapter’s inaugural spring reception <em>Celebrating Equity, Diversity, Inclusion, and Indigeneity (EDII) in the Chemical Sciences</em>. This event was open to the entire department, ranging from undergraduate students to faculty and staff. The goal was to organize a barrier-free and safe environment for the Queen’s chemistry community to network and discuss EDII. To make this event accessible and free-of-charge, the chapter secured ~$10,000 CAD of funding from several sources, including ACS, NanoFabrication Kingston, Public Service Alliance of Canada – 901, and Queen’s University.</p>

<p>The event was attended by ~100 people and included a formal reception and dinner in the Limestone City Ballroom at the Four Points by Sheraton Kingston. After the social hour, the attendees heard from chapter representatives and three keynote speakers: Dr. Racquel Jemison [Program Manager, ACS Office of Diversity (Video)]; Dr. Nicholas (Nick) Mosey [Associate Dean (Research) and Deputy Provost (Academic Operations and Inclusion), Queen’s University – Faculty of Arts and Science]; and Dr. Elliot Chapple [Director (EDII), Queen’s University – Faculty of Arts and Science]. The event concluded with an award ceremony honouring members of the Queen’s chemistry community through the <em>Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program and Chapter Excellence awards</em>.</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter's inaugural spring reception event">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/edii_event.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter's inaugural spring reception event" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter’s inaugural spring reception event

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Maximilian van Zyl</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Highlighting Women in STEM and the ACS WCC</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2022/06/29/wcc-event.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Highlighting Women in STEM and the ACS WCC" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-13T22:56:24+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2022/06/29/wcc-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2022/06/29/wcc-event.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>On June 28, 2022, Q-ACS celebrated the 95th anniversary of the ACS Women Chemists Committee (WCC). Q-ACS was awarded the largest possible grant offered by WCC to host an event. The grant stipulated that the event “must follow the WCC mission to ‘attract, retain, develop, promote, and advocate for women to positively impact diversity, equity, and inclusion in the [American Chemical] Society and the profession” and that “[t]he event must have at least 10 participants.” Q-ACS worked with other groups including the Department of Chemical Engineering, Gender Minorities in Physics (GEMINI-P), and QC-IDEAS to promote the event. It featured talks by 1) Dr. Amy Balija (ACS National WCC Chair) (Virtual) 2) Dr. Amanda Bongers (Queen’s Chemistry Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion Committee Chair) 3) Dr. Shoma Sinha (Queen’s Women’s Network and Queen’s Partnerships and Innovation) 4) Brooke Ring (Women in Science at Queen’s) and 5) Rachel Shum (Chemical Institute of Canada – Kingston Section). Q-ACS provided refreshments, and the event was nicely attended.</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="In-person invited speakers from left-to-right: Brooke Ring, Dr. Shoma Sinha, Rachel Shum, and Dr. Amanda Bongers">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/wcc_2022.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="In-person invited speakers from left-to-right: Brooke Ring, Dr. Shoma Sinha, Rachel Shum, and Dr. Amanda Bongers" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      In-person invited speakers from left-to-right: Brooke Ring, Dr. Shoma Sinha, Rachel Shum, and Dr. Amanda Bongers

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Daniel Reddy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>