<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-26T23:23:38+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Q-ACS</title><subtitle>Queen’s University International Student Chapter of the American Chemical Society (Q-ACS).</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Celebrating EDII in the Chemical Sciences</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating EDII in the Chemical Sciences" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-26T23:22:53+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>On March 30, 2023, Q-ACS hosted its largest event of 2022-2023: the chapter’s inaugural spring reception <em>Celebrating Equity, Diversity, Inclusion, and Indigeneity (EDII) in the Chemical Sciences</em>. This event was open to the entire department, ranging from undergraduate students to faculty and staff. The goal was to organize a barrier-free and safe environment for the Queen’s chemistry community to network and discuss EDII. To make this event accessible and free-of-charge, the chapter secured ~$10,000 CAD of funding from several sources, including ACS, NanoFabrication Kingston, Public Service Alliance of Canada – 901, and Queen’s University.</p>

<p>The event was attended by ~100 people and included a formal reception and dinner in the Limestone City Ballroom at the Four Points by Sheraton Kingston. After the social hour, the attendees heard from chapter representatives and three keynote speakers: Dr. Racquel Jemison [Program Manager, ACS Office of Diversity (Video)]; Dr. Nicholas (Nick) Mosey [Associate Dean (Research) and Deputy Provost (Academic Operations and Inclusion), Queen’s University – Faculty of Arts and Science]; and Dr. Elliot Chapple [Director (EDII), Queen’s University – Faculty of Arts and Science]. The event concluded with an award ceremony honouring members of the Queen’s chemistry community through the <em>Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program and Chapter Excellence awards</em>.</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter's inaugural spring reception event">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/edii_event.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter's inaugural spring reception event" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter’s inaugural spring reception event

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Maximilian van Zyl (Q-ACS Secretary)</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>