<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-26T23:31:04+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Q-ACS</title><subtitle>Queen’s University International Student Chapter of the American Chemical Society (Q-ACS).</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Celebrating EDII in the Chemical Sciences</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating EDII in the Chemical Sciences" /><published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-26T23:30:31+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2023/03/31/celebrating-edii-in-the-chemical-scienes.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>On March 30, 2023, Q-ACS hosted its largest event of 2022-2023: the chapter’s inaugural spring reception <em>Celebrating Equity, Diversity, Inclusion, and Indigeneity (EDII) in the Chemical Sciences</em>. This event was open to the entire department, ranging from undergraduate students to faculty and staff. The goal was to organize a barrier-free and safe environment for the Queen’s chemistry community to network and discuss EDII. To make this event accessible and free-of-charge, the chapter secured ~$10,000 CAD of funding from several sources, including ACS, NanoFabrication Kingston, Public Service Alliance of Canada – 901, and Queen’s University.</p>

<p>The event was attended by ~100 people and included a formal reception and dinner in the Limestone City Ballroom at the Four Points by Sheraton Kingston. After the social hour, the attendees heard from chapter representatives and three keynote speakers: Dr. Racquel Jemison [Program Manager, ACS Office of Diversity (Video)]; Dr. Nicholas (Nick) Mosey [Associate Dean (Research) and Deputy Provost (Academic Operations and Inclusion), Queen’s University – Faculty of Arts and Science]; and Dr. Elliot Chapple [Director (EDII), Queen’s University – Faculty of Arts and Science]. The event concluded with an award ceremony honouring members of the Queen’s chemistry community through the <em>Graduate Student and Postdoctoral Scholars Recognition Program and Chapter Excellence awards</em>.</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter's inaugural spring reception event">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/edii_event.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter's inaugural spring reception event" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Q-ACS president, Daniel Reddy, addressing attendees at the Chapter’s inaugural spring reception event

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Maximilian van Zyl (Q-ACS Secretary)</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Highlighting Women in STEM and the ACS WCC</title><link href="/Q-ACS-Website/2022/06/29/wcc-event.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Highlighting Women in STEM and the ACS WCC" /><published>2022-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-26T23:30:31+00:00</updated><id>/Q-ACS-Website/2022/06/29/wcc-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Q-ACS-Website/2022/06/29/wcc-event.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<!-- excerpt end -->

<p>On June 28, 2022, Q-ACS celebrated the 95th anniversary of the ACS Women Chemists Committee (WCC). Q-ACS was awarded the largest possible grant offered by WCC to host an event. The grant stipulated that the event “must follow the WCC mission to ‘attract, retain, develop, promote, and advocate for women to positively impact diversity, equity, and inclusion in the [American Chemical] Society and the profession” and that “[t]he event must have at least 10 participants.” Q-ACS worked with other groups including the Department of Chemical Engineering, Gender Minorities in Physics (GEMINI-P), and QC-IDEAS to promote the event. It featured talks by 1) Dr. Amy Balija (ACS National WCC Chair) (Virtual) 2) Dr. Amanda Bongers (Queen’s Chemistry Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion Committee Chair) 3) Dr. Shoma Sinha (Queen’s Women’s Network and Queen’s Partnerships and Innovation) 4) Brooke Ring (Women in Science at Queen’s) and 5) Rachel Shum (Chemical Institute of Canada – Kingston Section). Q-ACS provided refreshments, and the event was nicely attended.</p>

<div class="cols" style="--cols: 1">
  
    
    <div>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="In-person invited speakers from left-to-right: Brooke Ring, Dr. Shoma Sinha, Rachel Shum, and Dr. Amanda Bongers">
    <img src="/Q-ACS-Website/images/wcc_2022.jpg" style="
        width: auto;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="In-person invited speakers from left-to-right: Brooke Ring, Dr. Shoma Sinha, Rachel Shum, and Dr. Amanda Bongers" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/Q-ACS-Website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      In-person invited speakers from left-to-right: Brooke Ring, Dr. Shoma Sinha, Rachel Shum, and Dr. Amanda Bongers

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

</div>
  
</div>]]></content><author><name>Daniel Reddy (Q-ACS President)</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>